<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on Aidan Zabalo</title>
    <link>https://gitabaz.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on Aidan Zabalo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2022 07:26:54 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://gitabaz.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Research</title>
      <link>https://gitabaz.github.io/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gitabaz.github.io/research/</guid>
      <description>Research  Random Unitary Circuits: Measurement-driven phase transition I am interested in understanding the effect of projective measurements on the dynamics of entanglement in random quantum circuits. Recently, there have been many works, both numerical an analytical, demonstrating a dynamical quantum phase transition in the entanglement entropy driven by the competition of scrambling unitary dynamics and disentangling projective measurements. Below a critical value of the measurement rate $(p &amp;lt; p_c)$ the entanglement entropy scales with the volume of the subsystem while above $(p &amp;gt; p_c)$ the entanglement entropy scales with the area.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teaching</title>
      <link>https://gitabaz.github.io/teaching/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gitabaz.github.io/teaching/</guid>
      <description>Teaching  Current: Fall 2021 - N/A  Past: Summer 2019 - General Physics Lab II 206
Spring 2019 - Analytical Physics II Honors 124H
Fall 2018 - Analytical Physics I Honors 123H
Summer 2018 - General Physics Lab I 205
Spring 2018 - General Physics Lab II 206
Fall 2017 - Analytical Physics I 123
Summer 2017 - General Physics Lab II 206</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Combinatorics Through Complex Analysis</title>
      <link>https://gitabaz.github.io/blog/combinatorics-through-complex-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2022 07:26:54 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gitabaz.github.io/blog/combinatorics-through-complex-analysis/</guid>
      <description>In a recent project I came across the following problem: Evaluate $$ a_{N,z} = \sum_{\{\alpha\} \in \mathcal{A}_{N,z}} \prod_{\alpha} e^{-\frac{2\pi\eta\alpha}{N}}\tag{1} \label{eq:exact_az} $$ where $\mathcal{A}_{N,z}$ contains all sets with $z$ unique integers chosen from $\{1,\ldots,N\}$ and $\{\alpha\}$ labels a particular set. To clarify what this means, consider the case where $N = 4$ and $z=2$. The sum we are interested in runs over the terms $$ \mathcal{A}_{N=4,z=2} = \{ \{1,2\}, \{1,3\}, \{1,4\}, \{2,3\}, \{2,4\}, \{3,4\} \} $$ so that $$ a_{N=4,z=2} = e^{-\frac{2\pi\eta(1 + 2)}{N}} + e^{-\frac{2\pi\eta(1 + 3)}{N}} + e^{-\frac{2\pi\eta(1 + 4)}{N}} + e^{-\frac{2\pi\eta(2 + 3)}{N}} + e^{-\frac{2\pi\eta(2 + 4)}{N}} + e^{-\frac{2\pi\eta(3 + 4)}{N}}.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Random Matrix Theory - Basics</title>
      <link>https://gitabaz.github.io/blog/rmt-basics/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2019 17:41:16 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gitabaz.github.io/blog/rmt-basics/</guid>
      <description>Introduction The first time I heard the term Random Matrix Theory (RMT) was at the Wednesday physics colloquium given by one of the faculty members at Rutgers. Immediately, I was intrigued by the idea of bringing together two of the most useful concepts in math: statistics and linear algebra. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t obvious to me what we could learn from studying random matrices but the more research I did into the field, the more I realized that their usage was spreading across the different branches of science.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A New Site Using Hugo</title>
      <link>https://gitabaz.github.io/blog/a-new-site-using-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Sep 2019 15:09:07 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gitabaz.github.io/blog/a-new-site-using-hugo/</guid>
      <description>I have just finished setting up a basic site using Hugo, a static site generator written in Go. Being a static site generator, Hugo builds pages when you create content instead of dynamically, when a vistor requests a page. This leads to fast and secure pages that can be hosted anywhere. I stumbled upon Hugo while browsing a random users github pages (I can&amp;rsquo;t remember the name) and the concept seemed ideal for my purposes: A website easy to setup, use, and manage.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
